Local 1199 President Leon Davis Records 5206-PR
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- 1199 Pension Fund, 1951-1966 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  Contains local 1199 pension plan brochure, report on pension activity, trustees of local 1199 pension fund investment accounts, local 1199 pension fund trustees meeting agenda, secretary-treasurer's annual reports, local 1199 pension fund meeting minutes, local 1199 pension fund statement of financial condition, and article about the pension that was in the 1199 News. Also contains correspondence regarding pension fund trustees meeting and the appointment of new trustees.
- 1199 Staff, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Contains a resignation memo, an employee grievance case, and guild division staff assignments.
- 1199 Training Programs, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  Contains local 1199 tentative proposal for training, local 1199 training possibilities, correspondence regarding Health Service Mobility Study, existing training, the future training program, correspondence regarding hiring a training person, training program proposal, and a copy of GHI health issues newsletter.
- Endorsements, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  Contains correspondence with several government officials in regards to local 1199 endorsing their political campaigns. Also contains a list of political endorsements, a statement by local 1199 on Richard L. Ottinger, a press release about local 1199 backing a political candidate, and a telegram from a candidate thanking local 1199.
- Endorsements, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  Contains correspondence with several government officials in regards to local 1199 endorsing their political campaigns. Also contains a memorandum, telegram, statement, press release, and correspondence regarding local 1199's support of presidential candidate George McGovern.
- Executive Board, 1969-1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Contains income and expenses report, executive council annual report, list of national union staff, list of executive board members, letters of invitation for the executive board meeting, memo to all board members, and a list of employees earning more that $10,000 a year.
- Executive Council-Appeals, Requests, Hearings, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  Contains a revision of dues schedule, request to have a day off on black solidarity day, petition to have a case put on the Delegate Assembly agenda, secret ballot for changes in dues, and a letter of invitation to the executive council for the retired members annual banquet.
- Executive Council-Appeals, Requests, Hearings, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  Contains letter and correspondence with various political, religious, civil rights, health and other groups including other unions, regarding event invitations and donation requests. Contains form letters and contribution receipts. Contains petitions from local 1199 members to executive council regarding pay board decision.
- Executive Council-Appeals, Requests, Hearings, 1966-1969 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  Contains a memorandum to area directors regarding executive council decision, a complaint filed from a union member, petitions from local 1199 members to have certain issues put on the Delegate Assembly agenda, a petition to amend the local 1199 constitution, a petition to change the payroll system, and a petition from retirees asking for increases in their pensions.
- French Polyclinic Health Center, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  Contains form letters, pamphlets, telegrams, and correspondence with local 144 and the French Polyclinic hospital regarding the merger of the two hospitals and which union will get jurisdiction over all the union employees. Also contains a copy of the local 144 hospital pension plan, and a sheet with the number of union employees at the French and Polyclinic hospitals.
- Gouverneur Health Service Program Dispute, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  Contains a statement issued by local 1199 with respect to Gouverneur Health Services Program, contains a petition from Gouverneur Health Services Program employees, contains statement from the fired union members, and contains correspondence with lawyers regarding why local 1199 will not support the Gouverneur workers.
- Guest Appearance on "Direct Line", 1968 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  Contains a transcript of what was said when Leon Davis was on the talk show "Direct Line".
- Health and Hospital Corporation, 1967-1971 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  Contains memorandum and correspondence with New York City Health and Hospital Corporation regarding affiliation contracts for hospital workers. Also contains newspaper articles and brochures discussing the conflict between 1199 and the NYC Health and Hospital Corporation, a supplemental agreement, affiliation memorandums, and proposed amendments to the local 1199 constitution.
- Health and Hospital Corporation, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  Contains correspondence with New York City Health and Hospital Corporation regarding affiliation contracts for hospital workers. Contains telegrams about 1199 strike rumors, arbitration case, rollback of affiliation non-professional employees, a memorandum of understanding between the department of hospitals and the district council, a transcript from a talk show featuring the Health and Hospital Corporation, and press releases.
- Health-Medical Care, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  Contains a statement of Jesse Olsen-Vice-President local 1199, new job description, notice of public hearing on health manpower, transcript of Davis' testimony, journal article, correspondence with state senate, statement by Davis, and a schedule of hospital inclusive plan rates.
- Health-Medical Care, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  Contains letters requesting Davis to testify at state senate Executive Session and a notice of Executive Session.
- Hospital League-Local 1199 Training and Upgrading Fund, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  Contains correspondence with students, hospitals, accountants, professors, the Training and Upgrading Fund, and government officials regarding a training conference to be put on by the Fund. Also contains financial statements, resumes, memorandums, agenda, list of applicants and meeting minutes.
- Hospital League-Local 1199 Training and Upgrading Fund, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  Contains correspondence with colleges, hospitals, the Department of Labor, and the Training and Upgrading Fund, regarding a training conference to be put on by the Fund. Also contains meeting minutes, agendas, a list of applicants, agreements, contracts, applicant information, and newspaper clippings.
- Hospital League-Local 1199 Training and Upgrading Fund, 1970-1972 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  Contains correspondence with the Training and Upgrading Fund. Also contains financial statements, meeting minutes, and annual reports.
- Hospital Model Contract, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence with lawyers regarding revisions to the model contract. Also contains index to contracts and articles of agreement.
- Hospital Negotiations, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  Contains correspondence with the State Mediations Board, the 1199 Delegate Assembly, the League of Voluntary Hospitals, and 1199 members regarding negotiation of the collective bargaining agreement. Also contains collective bargaining stipulations, committee on negotiations meeting minutes, contract demands on behalf of hospitals, 1199 contract ratifications, a confidential bulletin, flyers, telegrams, a notice of entry, a memorandum, a summary of gains in the new contract, a transcript of the public hearings, contract changes proposed by 1199 membership, a proposal, a statement by Davis, contract expirations, and a strike plan.
- Hospital Negotiations, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence with congressmen, lawyers, the Institute for Mediation and Conflict Resolution, and Mayor Lindsay, 1199 members, the League of Voluntary Hospitals, and 1199 members regarding the collective bargaining agreement. Also contains notice of hearing from the Department of Labor, a transcript of an arbitration, a summary of gains from the new contract, the Department of Labor recommendations, a memorandum, and index of benefits, an invitation, a poem, a telegram, list of lunch reimbursements, a statement by Davis, a letter to the New York Times, a press release, and a proposal for contract renewal.
- Hospitals, 1964-1970 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  Contains a letter from lawyers including arbitration proceedings. Contains correspondence with universities, and lawyers. Also contains an arbitration decision, telegrams, an order to show cause, the Hospital Executives Club membership roster, and a paper written by Theodore Kheel.
- Hospitals, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  Contains correspondence with lawyers, the city of New York, universities, and hospitals regarding contracts, work stoppages, and union member issues. Also contains court proceedings and decisions, and union flyers.
- Hospitals, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  Contains correspondence with 1199 members, hospitals, the IRS, and the AFL-CIO regarding labor contracts, strikes, and union representatives. Also contains telegrams, a supplemental clause to an agreement, and news clipping.
- Hospitals, 1967-1969 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  Contains correspondence with New York Medical College regarding financial problems. Also contains correspondence with universities, hospitals and lawyers regarding terms of the labor contract. Contains a list of hospital rates, a publication called The Effect of Unions on Hospital Management, and a magazine article.
- Housing, 1964-1966 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  Contains correspondence with government officials, non-profit housing groups regarding fair housing initiatives. Also contains news clippings on local housing issues.
- Housing--Union Sponsorship, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  Contains correspondence with government officials, the Housing and Development Administration, lawyers, architects, and contractors regarding the East River Urban Renewal Project sponsored by 1199. Also contains memorandums, telegrams, meeting minutes and a list of applicants to help sponsor the project.
- Jewish Currents Dinner, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  Contains correspondence with the Jewish Currents publication regarding a dinner where Davis is scheduled to speak. Also contains Davis' introduction and his speech at the event plus an article written about the event in a Jewish newspaper.
- Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  Contains the following publications by the Department of Labor: State Labor Relations Acts and the Second Annual Report of the Advisory Council on the Labor and Management Improper Practices Act. Also contains a pamphlet called Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959, a pamphlet called Understanding the 1959 Labor Law, and a pamphlet called Labor Organization Information Reporting. Contains a memorandum from General Counsel and a statement by the National Lawyers Guild about the Act. Contains newspaper articles, telegrams, and correspondence with other labor organizations regarding the new Act.
- League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y., 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  Contains a copy of the collective bargaining agreement with the League, correspondence with lawyers and the League, and a list of members of the League.
- League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y., 1970-1972 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  Contains a copy of the collective bargaining agreement between the League of Voluntary Hospitals and Local 1199. Contains correspondence with the League of Voluntary Hospitals regarding terms of the collective bargaining agreement. Also contains letters from hospitals who have recently joined the League. Contains report from the Impasse Panel.
- League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y., 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  Contains a copy of the collective bargaining agreement between the League of Voluntary Hospitals and Local 1199. Contains correspondence with the League of Voluntary Hospitals regarding terms of the collective bargaining agreement.
- League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y.--Union Arbitration., 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  Contains correspondence with the League, lawyers, the State Board of Mediation, and the mayor's office regarding arbitration cases. Also contains a settlement agreement, a list of exclusions by agreement, a copy of the Local 1199 benefit plan, financial reports, and arbitration briefs.
- League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y.--Union Committees., 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  Contains correspondence with the League regarding the formation of the following for committees: Training and Upgrading, Job Study-Inequity, Hiring Hall-Recruitment, and Pension. Contains a list of who is in each committee.
- League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y.--Training and Upgrading Committee, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  Contains correspondence with the League, the training committee, and various government and non-profit organizations regarding the formation of an Advisory Committee for the training committee. Also contains resumes.
- League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y.--Training and Upgrading Committee., 1969 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  Contains correspondence with the training committee, universities, and hospitals regarding recruitment, new programs, and meetings. Also contains telegrams, a memorandum, a list of institutions participating in the program, meeting minutes, a report on the training program and an agreement and declaration of trust.
- Legal Opinions, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Legislation, 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  Contains correspondence with lawyers, and government organizations and officials regarding certain legislation such as the Health Security Act. Also contains a copy of a bill (National Public Employee Relations Act), the Health Security Act and a memorandum.
- Legislation, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  Contains correspondence with lawyers, and government organizations and officials regarding certain legislation such as anti-busing bills. Also contains a proposal for amending labor laws in regards to nursing homes, and a memorandum.
- Local 1199 B- Charleston, 1969-1971 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence between Davis and organizers of 1199 B in Charleston, SC regarding problems in Charleston and the establishment of the chapter. Also contains 1199 B financial statements and list of things to be done in Charleston.
- Local 1199 C- Philadelphia, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  Contains correspondence between Davis, lawyers, and organizers of 1199 C in Philadelphia, PA regarding union members, collective bargaining agreements, traffic violations, financial matters, and affiliation with RWDSU. Also contains copy of 1199ers United.
- Local 1199 C- Philadelphia, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  Contains death certificate and funeral bill for Norman Rayford, a union organizer for 1199 C who was shot by a security guard during an 1199 C rally. Also contains a card from Rayford's wife. Contains correspondence between Davis and 1199 C regarding stolen goods, 1199 C expenses and renovation.
- Local 1199 Credit Union, 1970-1972 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  Contains correspondence with lawyers, the League of Voluntary Hospitals, and 1199 members regarding the establishment of a credit union to deduct union dues automatically from members' paychecks. Also contains a deduction check off list, 1199 credit union financial reports, and an oath taken by committee members of the credit union.
- Local 1199 E-Baltimore, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  Contains correspondence with lawyers, 1199 E, and accountants regarding financial situation, collective bargaining agreements, and the national union. Also contains financial statements, the 1199 E newsletter, and internal disputes plan, and meeting minutes.
- Local 1199 E-Baltimore, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  Contains correspondence with 1199 E, Davis and lawyers regarding financial matters, strikes, union issues, and by-laws. Also contains 1199 E administrative rules, financial reports, a proposal, a petition, meeting minutes, election results, and proposed 1199 E by-laws.
- 1199 Financial Reports, 1965-1968 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  Contains 1199 reports, 1199 statements of financial condition, and 1199 financial reports. Also contains correspondence with accountants.
- Local 1199 Financial Reports, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  Contains a financial report and national union budget.
- Local 1199 Housing Project, 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  Contains a petition sent to mayor Lindsay regarding the renewal of an area in NYC. Contains memorandum from lawyer regarding 1199 housing- community facilities. Contains correspondence with government officials, the Housing and Development Administration, lawyers, architects, and developers regarding various housing projects including the East River Urban Renewal Project, sponsored by 1199. Also contains news clipping.
- Local 1199 Housing Program, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  Contains correspondence with government officials, the Housing and Development Administration, lawyers, architects, and developers regarding the East River Urban Renewal Project. Also contains meeting minutes, the Calendar of the Board of Estimate of The City of New York, and an agreement.
- Local 1199 Housing Program, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence with government officials, the Housing and Development Administration, lawyers, architects, and developers regarding 1199 housing corporation and the East River Urban Renewal Project. Also contains an information bulletin on the 1199 housing corporation, and a memorandum on the East River Urban Renewal Project.
- Local 1199 Massachusetts, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  Contains correspondence with union regarding the national union and contains financial statement.
- Local 1199 P-Pittsburgh, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  Contains correspondence between Davis, lawyers, and organizers of 1199 C in Philadelphia, PA regarding union members, collective bargaining agreements, and an arbitration case with the University of Pittsburgh. Contains copy of the arbitration and the attorney's ruling.
- Local 1199 Staff, 1966-1969 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  Contains letters from staff members to Davis submitting their resignation or discussing personal issues.
- Local 1199 Staff, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  Contains correspondence, petitions and memorandums between union members and Davis regarding the layoff of a staff member and various other personal and work related issues. Also contains a list of staff members.
- Local 1199 Union Headquarters, 1969-1971 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  Contains correspondence with architects, insurance company, and artist regarding building the new 1199 headquarters. Also contains drawings, invoices, and brochures.
- Memorandums, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  Contains memorandums regarding meetings, trainings, arbitrations, picket lines, food, furniture, collective bargaining agreements, employee issues, wages, contracts, rallies, bills, and more. Also contains letter from lawyers.
- Memorandums, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  Contains memorandums regarding staff expenses, parties, complaints, financial reports, elections, wages, meetings, rallies and boycotts, furniture, reimbursements, training, arbitration, invitations, complaints, and more.
- Minimum Wage, 1964-1966 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence with government officials and unions, memorandums and telegrams regarding increasing the minimum wage. Also contains correspondence with lawyers and a brief of a court case involving 1199 as interveners between the City of New York and Prudential Laundry Corporation.
- Montefiore Hospital, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  Contains Montefiore Hospital and Medical Center Third Annual Report.
- NLRB-Compliance Taft Hartley, 1953-1958 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  Contains letters from 1199 lawyers notifying them that they need to fill out forms to remain in compliance with the Taft Hartley laws.
- National Union Conference, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence, invitations, brochures, and financial statements regarding the National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees Conference in December of 1971.
- National Union -Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  Contains correspondence with AFL-CIO unions regarding loans, and correspondence with 1199 members who reached out to Davis for help. Also contains 1199 operating budget for 1970, the envelope stock for all of the 1199 branches across the country, and a request to Davis to be an Impartial Umpire in a labor dispute.
- National Union Founding Conference, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  Contains correspondence with lawyers and government officials regarding the establishment of a National Hospital and Nursing Home Employees division of 1199. Also contains income and expense report for the national organizing committee and for 1199 B, conference invitations, a conference agenda, list of conference attendants, confirmation from the conference hotel and catering service, a state of the union report, and a newspaper clipping.
- National Union Membership Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  Contains a memorandum regarding the National Union Membership Report for November 1970. National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees Membership Report for November 1970, October 1970, May 1970, June 1970, July 1970, August 1970, and September 1970.
- National Union Memorandums, 1969-1971 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  Contains memorandums to 1199 members about union policies, financial reports, legal issues, conferences, phone bills or about reports that need to be made.
- National Union Memorandums, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  Contains memorandums regarding union policies, and new technology. Also contains summary of National Union Strike and Defense Fund.
- Negotiation Committee Minutes, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  Contains negotiation committee meeting minutes and proposals for the 1972 contract.
- New Jersey AFL-CIO, 1966-1968 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  Contains invitation to New Jersey AFL-CIO conference, a copy of the 1968 legislative program sponsored by the New Jersey State AFL-CIO, correspondence with the New Jersey AFL-CIO regarding advice on resolutions, strike funds, and union events. Also contains New Jersey AFL-CIO election information, and the constitution of the New Jersey State AFL-CIO.
- N.Y.C Central Labor Council, 1964-1966 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  Contains correspondence with the NYC Central Labor Council regarding strikes, civil rights laws, organizing taxi cab drivers, meetings, and elections. Also contains a telegram and a receipt.
- N.Y.C Central Labor Council, 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  Contains correspondence with the NYC Central Labor Council regarding meetings, conferences, dinners, mass demonstrations, payroll taxes, strikes and wage freezes. Also contains a telegram, a memorandum about the Governor's Program Bill, and a list of NYC Central Labor Council officers.
- N.Y.C Central Labor Council, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  Contains correspondence with the NYC Central Labor Council regarding strikes, advertisements, and parties/events.
- NYC School Strike, 1967-1969 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  Contains telegrams, correspondence, statements, pamphlets, and summaries regarding a teachers union strike in NYC during salary negotiations. Also contains correspondence with southern groups regarding voting rights of African Americans in Mississippi.
- NY Urban Coalition, 1969-1971 (Box 21, Folder 15)